Donald Gaxho

Brookline, NH



dgaxho@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/dongaxho

Summary

I'm a software engineer with a passion for mobile development, and 10 years of experience in the field. I'm excited to bring unique ideas to life that push the envelope of mobile technology, while keeping code performant, easy to work on, and in tune with the flow of the teams that make it happen.

While my strength has always been focused on iOS native development. I also have experience with Flutter crossplatform and Android native development. On various teams, I have fit the roles of individual contributor, team lead, and technical manager.

Right now, I'm leading a mobile development team building apps that provide life changing medical treatment in patients' homes, at Medically Home.

Experience



Lead Mobile Engineer

Medically Home

Sep 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

- * Introduced high coverage comprehensive unit testing that has significantly reduced the number of defects that have been caught by QA, improving our overall development velocity, and ensuring a 0 issue experience with our patients.
- * Introduced GraphQL as a process for well specified API endpoints that reduce the possibility of data mismatch issues between client apps and our API platform.
- * Have worked on evaluating and integrating new medical devices via Bluetooth Low Energy.

Mobile Staff Engineer

Appcues

Jan 2019 - Mar 2020 (1 year 3 months)

- * Led development and release of a beta version of Appcues' onboarding and product experience tool for native iOS apps, making it possible to create dynamic onboarding and messaging flows to highlight new app features without requiring app store releases.
- * Architected and contributed to the iOS SDK while also working with product and design to plan the project. Defined REST APIs via OpenAPI to ensure that web front end, backend, and the SDK could be developed in parallel.

Agency Development Manager

LevelUp

Jan 2017 - Dec 2018 (2 years)

* Managed iOS and Android development at LevelUp's Agency team, while still contributing primarily on the iOS SDK. Led teams of 3 iOS and 3 Android devs in supporting hundreds of client apps. Made improvements to both the SDK and development workflow to ensure we could scale out to continue building SDK features while maintaining support for our many clients.

ILEVEIUP iOS Developer

LevelUp

Sep 2013 - Jan 2017 (3 years 5 months)

* Joined as an iOS engineer when LevelUp's Angecy team supported just 2-3 clients and the SDK was still in infancy. Added features and enhancements to the SDK including campaigns, rewards, payment options and more and worked on custom features for dozens of client iOS apps.



🥦 Software Engineer

Fidelity Investments

Apr 2010 - Jul 2013 (3 years 4 months)

- * Participated in a 6 month training phase that culminated in contributing to the development of a production ready flagship personalized brokerage and 401k portfolio web app.
- * Developed a native proof of concept iPad app that allows managers to gain a geolocation-based perspective of their organization hierarchy, view key metrics on sites, sub-managers and employee types, and manage the data through an intuitive filtering system. Was fully responsible for all Obj-C/ CocoaTouch based code.
- * With the company's main mobile team, shipped the 2.0 version of Fidelity's iPhone app, working on trade alerts, watch lists and accounts, among various other components. In this process, also worked on improvements to the current iPad app.
- * Contributed to Fidelity's Account Opening iPad project, which utilized a unique XML driven UI / Application Logic architecture that could be modified server side without pushing changes to the app store.

Ul Engineer Intern

LabCentrix LLC

Jan 2009 - Apr 2009 (4 months)

* Created UI mockups for a lab instrument & experiment management tool using Adobe Fireworks. Built an Adobe Flex prototype of the app based on the selected mockup.

Education



WPI Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science 2006 - 2010

Skills

Swift (Programming Language) • iOS • Kotlin • Software Engineering • Objective-C • Albanian • SDK • Flutter • GraphQL • Android